George AmoahBoahene 055-555-2783 | gaboahene1@gmail.com |

Software Engineer

linkedin.com/in/george-boahene-1z/ | github.com/olibo1zeemoni | website

Summary

iOS Software Engineer with 4+ years building consumer health & productivity apps. Strong experience with HealthKit, Core Motion, SwiftUI charts, and modern concurrency (Combine + async/await). Comfortable owning features end-to-end, architecture, implementation, testing, accessibility, and App Store delivery.

SKILLS

Programming Languages Swift, C, Python, JavaScript.

Development Platforms Apple Platforms, Vapor, Node.js, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Git Apple-Specific Skills SwiftUI, UIKit, AppKit, Swift Concurrency, Combine, Core Bluetooth, Core Data, Xcode Instruments, XCTest, Composable Architecture (TCA), Swift Package Manager, CocoaPods

EDUCATION

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology (2015) Major: Electrical/Electronics Engineering (B.Sc.)

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Realm | iOS Software Engineer | November 2021 - Present

- Perform code and API reviews across all iOS engineering teams
- Led a four-person development team responsible for user networking features throughout the product
- Review Apps for user experience issues, reproducing bugs, and resolving them.
- Rewrote and modernized the internal software development onboarding flow, documentation, and resources
- Play a key role in migrating architecture to Combine, Swift Package Manager, and Composable Architecture

Zipline | Flight Operations Engineer | July 2019 - October 2021

- · Flight Operations.
- Build/Assemble Battery packs for Unmanned Aerial Vehicles.
- Perform routine and non-routine maintenance on Li-ion battery packs.
- · Maintenance of aircraft and ground systems.

D'Appolonia JV | Electrical Engineer(intern) | September 2018 - June 2019

- Training on Programmable Logic Controllers(Siemens).
- Reading and interpretation of piping and instrumentation diagrams.

ES Emizon | Field Application Engineer | October 2016 - August 2018

- Assist customers in designing and optimizing security systems, including access control, surveillance, and intrusion detection.
- Handle commissioning, troubleshooting, maintenance, and upgrades of installed security systems.

Nestlé | Electrical Engineer | September 2015 - August 2016

Installation of Electrical and Mechanical Equipment according to the manufacturer's manual.

- Performed risk assessment analysis for jobs on-site.
- Oversaw routine maintenance tasks and kept detailed records.

PROJECTS

SleepWave An iOS app built with UIKit, SwiftUI, and HealthKit that employs contactless motion-sensing technology to help users unwind, monitor sleep stages, and identify potential sleep issues for a more restful and insightful night's sleep.

MirrorType An iOS and iPadOS keyboard app built with SwiftUI, UIKit, Combine, and CloudKit that lets friends send fun, upside-down (mirrored) text instantly between devices for playful messaging and surprise conversations.

Lead the Way An indoor navigation iOS app for the visually impaired, written in Swift using Core Motion and custom algorithms requiring no GPS or external devices, using a Vapor backend (Senior Design project)

Plus Plus A counter app for watchOS using SwiftUI, Combine, watch complications, and local storage

Fury Frenzy A collection of retro games for iPhone, iPad, and Mac built using SwiftUI and UIKit

Taipu A SwiftUI watchOS Pokémon type checker app with haptic feedback and Digital Crown integration

Buddy A privacy-first peer-to-peer messaging app for iOS built with SwiftUI, enabling seamless communication via Bluetooth and Wi-Fi when the internet is unavailable.

COMMUNITY

Involvement Mentor for <u>Underdog Devs</u>, Hacking With Swift **Open-Source** Swift Algorithm Club (Swift), Xi Editor (macOS)